# Brian Pham | Fullstack Developer

I am a Fullstack Developer with 6 years of experience building a small business seeking to convert my proven business development skills into software development. I specialize in **MongoDB**, **Express**, **React**, **Node** (**MERN**) and **Django** fullstack web development to build applications alongside API systems. I am a lifelong student that is always looking to improve myself both personally and professionally each day. I believe my ability to work in collaborative environments with transparent communication skills make me an excellent developer.

#### **Skills**

Languages - JavaScript, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, HTML, CSS, EJS, DTL, C++, Java

Database - PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Other - RESTful Routing, JSON, Stripe API, Amazon Web Services (AWS)

Libraries and Frameworks - React (class based and hooks), Express.js, Django, jQuery, Bootstrap, Semantic UI, Bulma

## **Software Development Projects**

June 2021 - PRESENT

The Exhibit - Full-stack ecommerce/social media hybrid application to share, like, comment, purchase and sell art.

- Singlehandedly executed the development of a full-stack hybrid ecommerce/social media website harnessing the MEN (MongoDB/Mongoose, Express.js, Node.js) stack, CSS, Javascript, EJS, HTML, and Bootstrap.
- Implemented Stripe API to manage secure payment processing and PicSum API to seed user content.
- Employed Amazon Web Services (AWS) cloud storage and Multer to handle file upload and image storage.

Wayfarer - Full-stack blog application where users can create articles and make comments on their world travels.

- Utilized the **Django framework, PostgreSQL database, Python, DTL, and Bootstrap** to build a RESTful application.
- Engaged with clients with daily morning check-ins and afternoon standups to develop a project while navigating clients' feature list to launch on **Heroku**.
- Proactively coordinated a team of three to execute user story sprints and wireframes as designed by the clients.

Ticket Diary - Full-stack social media website where users can discuss, like, favorite, and share their love of film.

- Applied RESTful programming with a MEN (MongoDB, Express.js, Node.js) stack to handle create, read, update, and delete (CRUD) operations.
- Reverse engineered the social media websites Instagram and Imgur and made improvements to their user experience, increasing the amount of viewable media at once and improving information flow per post.
- Collaborated in a team of two to specialize in application development as well as exercise pair programming skills.
- Implemented user authentication, authorization, and sessions in the backend for security to verify and restrict clients from accessing unauthorized portions of the application.

## **Professional Experience**

Tiffany's Cosmetics - Business Owner | Los Angeles, California

July 2015 - Present

- Spearheaded the transformation of a family-owned brick-and-mortar store to an online business, expanding the customer base from local to international, increasing gross annual sales by nearly 200%.
- Created and strategically marketed a successful online business with over \$250,000 in gross annual sales and nearly 8000 transactions annually.
- Reduced employee work hours by 70%, decreased commute times by 80%, improving employee physical health and overall morale.
- Oversaw and managed more than 2,000 unique items with over 5,000 total items in inventory while evaluating sales records, changing market demands and trends.
- Consolidated business expenses by removing rent payments for a physical storefront yielding the business an immediate \$24,000 annual savings; further reduced business expenses by proactively investigating supply costs and negotiating with suppliers.

Dr. Lawren Sack's Laboratory - Research Assistant | University of California, Los Angeles Sept 2013 - January 2014

- Analyzed and researched leaf specimens that contributed to the publication of several scientific papers.
- Collaborated with peers to efficiently coordinate division of labor on an astounding amount of data review of more than 2,000 samples.
- Measured and mapped systems of leaf hydraulics that provided insight into crop and plant survival during periods of drought.

### **EDUCATION**

#### **General Assembly**

June 2021 - September 2021

## **Software Engineering Immersive**

Full-stack software engineering immersive student in an intensive, twelve-week, 480+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

## **University of California, Los Angeles**

#### Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Biology | Specialization in Computer Science

Alpha Lambda Delta Honor Society, Phi Eta Sigma Honor Society

Computer Science coursework included: 3 Courses of C++ | 1 Course of Web Development (Javascript, mySQL) | 1 Course of Python | 1 Course of Java